volvooceanracegame.com 2015-09-06

# Privacy Policy | Volvo Ocean Race 2014-2015

**PRIVACY POLICY for www.volvooceanrace.com**

**Data Protection Compliance – our commitment to you**

In order to protect your privacy, the Volvo Ocean Race (VOR) seeks to comply with the applicable Data Protection regulations, in particular Organic Law 15/1999, of 13 December, governing Personal Data Protection and Royal Decree 1720/2007, of 21 December, which approves the Regulations that implement Organic Law 15/1999. We follow the appropriate security procedures in the storage and disclosure of personal information so as to prevent unauthorised access by third parties, in accordance to the level of protection, the nature of the data supplied and considering the state of the technology. We also require those parties to whom we transfer personal information to comply with the same. However, the Internet is not a totally secure medium and you acknowledge and agree that we shall not be responsible for any unauthorised use, distribution, damage or destruction of personal data, except to the extent we are required to accept such responsibility by applicable laws.

The information you may supply to us will be included in an automated file for the purpose of providing services to you or for direct marketing by us or by our Race partners as detailed below.

For more information about the data controller, please visit the “Contact us” section.

The files that contain personal data are registered in the Spanish Data Protection Agency's Register.

**Definitions  
** Agents means companies or individuals contracted by Volvo to provide database and marketing services to and for the Volvo Ocean Race. These companies or individuals are bound by Volvo’s terms and conditions for collecting your personal information.

Volvo Group means the subsidiary companies of VCC and ABV, namely Volvo Cars, Volvo Trucks, Volvo Buses, Volvo Construction Equipment, Volvo Penta, Volvo Aero, Volvo Financial Services

Race Partners means Volvo Car Corporation and AB Volvo Group; race partners Inmarsat, Boston Consulting Group, Abu Dhabi Tourism Authority and DHL; race sponsors Thrane & Thrane and IWC Schaffhausen; race suppliers Puma, Volvo Penta, Volvo IT and Ericsson. This is not an exclusive list of the Volvo Ocean Race Partners – VOR reserves the right to add other sponsors and suppliers to this list at any time.

You will find further information about our Race partners on the Partners page.

**When do we collect information and how do we process it?  
** From time to time the Volvo Ocean Race may invite you to supply personal information (e.g. name, email address and country) in order for us to provide you with certain services such as event updates and newsletters, register for subscriber-only services, downloads, play games, enter sweepstakes or competitions, participate in Race Partner surveys or shop online. This information will be collected from you at a 'Registration Page'. In order to deliver such services, we will need to process and store your personal information and may need to transfer it to companies in the Volvo Group, relevant partners or agents of the Volvo Ocean Race or Third Party Sponsors for processing both inside and outside the European Economic Area (EEA). By submitting your personal information you consent to such processing and transfers in connection with such services and for any other purposes to which you consent at the time you provide the information or as provided in this privacy policy. Please note that countries outside the EEA may not have the same level of protection as countries within the EEA, but Volvo Ocean Race always demands that those parties to whom we transfer data adhere to the same security procedures that it follows itself.

Your personal information may also be used to better understand who visits the sites. This allows us to improve our content on an ongoing basis, and report on audience levels. All such reporting information will be aggregated, anonymous data. We may provide analysis of such data about our users, sales, traffic patterns and related site information to our Agents or Race Partners, but this data will not contain any information about you from which you could be identified.

Also, we may transfer your personal information to purchasers or subsidiaries (and potential purchasers or subsidiaries) if VOR acquires, or is acquired by or merged with, another company. This will enable you, for example, to continue your relationship with the Volvo Ocean Race despite a change of ownership.

If you do not agree with this privacy policy you should not submit your personal information on this website.

**How will we use your data?  
** Your data will be used to facilitate a number of different services which have been mentioned above. In all cases, all data capture points will clearly detail what types of information we are collecting about you, as well as the uses the Volvo Ocean Race intends to make of this information, most of which have been set out in this privacy policy.

**Registration Page**

**\- Volvo Opt-In  
** You will be given the option to register your details on the website in order to receive email updates or downloads from VOR, as well as other information related to the Volvo Ocean Race and to be provided with the services referred to above. The information we need for us to provide these various services to you, are usually your name, email address and country.

To complete registration you are required to check the Privacy Policy opt-in box, to indicate that you agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy.

You may also be given the option to provide additional information which allows us to tailor the communications or services we send to you or can provide to you to fit your specific interests. We may use the information we collect about you to notify you from time to time about updates on the Volvo Ocean Race and important new features related to the Volvo Ocean Race as well as changes to our on-line services, special offers, sweepstakes, competitions, surveys or promotions and other programs and events we think you will find of interest.

At any time you may stop emails being sent to your email address from VOR by opting-out. To find out how to do this, please refer to the section below entitled: "Unsubscribe”.

**\- Volvo Race Sponsor Opt-In  
** During registration, you may be asked if you'd like to receive information from one of our Volvo Ocean Race Partners.

If you check this opt-in box, we may send your information to our Race Partners.

Our Race Partners may contact you via email regarding their products and services, to that extend you will be required to check an opt-in box. Under no circumstances will we share your personal data with any other third parties who are not listed as a Race Partner.

We are not responsible for the privacy practices of our Race Partners and this statement applies solely to any personal information collected by us.

**Online Purchases  
** When you place an order we need to know your name, phone number, email address, billing address, and credit card type, number and expiration date. This allows us to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status. Your information is treated with the utmost security. Your information is used by the Volvo Ocean Race and its agents for the purpose of aggregate identification of our customers. Your personal information will not be delivered to any third party, unless you authorize us specifically to do this. PLEASE NOTE THAT ON-LINE SALES WILL BE PROCESSED SUBJECT TO SEPARATE TERMS AND CONDITIONS THAT WILL BE MADE AVAILABLE TO YOU DURING YOUR TRANSACTION.

When you place orders or access your account information, we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software (SSL) encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. All of the customer data we collect is protected against unauthorized access.

**Unsubscribe  
** To unsubscribe, login into your profile page and deselect the items to which you have subscribed. Click update.

**Cookies  
** Cookies are bits of information that a website transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. The use of cookies is an industry standard practice, which you'll find at most major websites. Cookies make web-surfing easier for you by saving your preferences while you're at our site or when you return.

In places where the Volvo Ocean Race site asks for login information (such as games), cookies may store your login name and password on your hard drive to eliminate the need for you to enter this information every time it is required.

The Volvo Ocean Race also uses cookies to understand site usage and patterns. This may include the use of your registration information to better understand and serve the interests of our users.

**What happens if you disable your cookies?  
** There may be features in our site which are not accessible without cookies. However, if you want to disable your cookies you can do so in two ways: you can ask your browser to inform you every time a cookie is set and then decide whether to accept it or not, or you can set your browser to automatically deny cookies.

If you ask your browser to inform you of "cookie set" requests and you say "NO" to the cookies, you will get a pop up window for every hit. If you set your browser to automatically deny cookies then you will not see these pop up windows.

**IP Address  
** We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address may also be used to gather broad demographic information.

**Links to Other Sites  
** This site contains links to other sites not operated by or on behalf of the Volvo Ocean Race. The Volvo Ocean Race is not responsible for the privacy practices of such websites and does not endorse or accept any responsibility for the content of such websites.

**Children's Guidelines  
** The Volvo Ocean Race does not specifically target children to register. However, should someone register on our site and tell us they are 14 or younger (where age is asked) they will not be added to our database and Volvo Ocean Race will be unable to use the personal data for the uses described in this privacy policy.

**Rights of access, rectification erasure and objection  
** The rights of access, rectification, erasure and objection shall be exercised in accordance with the applicable laws.

You may exercise these rights by submitting a written or e-mailed request accompanied by copy of your identification document, to the following address:

Volvo Ocean Race, S.L.U  
Muelle nº 10 de Levante  
Puerto de Alicante  
03001 Alicante - Spain

Or by email to: [info@volvooceanrace.com](mailto:info@volvooceanrace.com)

If you have any concerns at all about any aspect of the management of personal data by us please contact us at the above address.
